A Guide to the Dunmore County Revolutionary War papers, 1775-1814
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Dunmore County Revolutionary War Papers, 1775-1814
Library of Virginia
21127
44 leaves, negative and positive photostats
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Lent for copying by William Twyman Williams, Hampden-Sidney, Virginia, 30 November 1934.
Scope and Content
Dunmore County Revolutionary War papers, 1775-1814, collected by William Twyman Williams (1775-1814) of Prince Edward County, Virginia, consisting of items pertaining to Dunmore County during the early years of the Revolutionary War. It includes accounts of salt purchases made under the auspices of the county Committee of Safety, militia lists, letters regarding militia appointments and one Loyalist declaration. Included also are returns for five districts in a 1775 county census and two militia commissions for the Shenandoah County, Virginia, militia during the War of 1812.
Arrangement
Arranged chronologically.
Contents List
- Deposition, 7 February 1775, of Alexander Machir, of Dunmore County, Virginia, regarding a proposed sale of tea by William Holliday., 1 leaf, negative photostat.
- Subscription list, 23 May 1775, for an unidentified fund. Written in German., 2 leaves, positive and negative photostat copies of same item.
- Roster, 29 May 1775, of Captain Jacob Holeman's militia company of Dunmore County., 2 leaves, negative photostats.
- Affidavit, 5 July 1775, of William Clarke stating his loyalist affiliation., 1 leaf, negative photostat.
- Letter, 12 September 1775, from R. Rutherford, Dunmore County, to unknown recipient concerning a meeting of the Committee of Safety for Dunmore County to appoint militia officers., 1 leaf, negative photostat.
- Census, November 1775, of a district in Dunmore County made by Richard Campbell., 1 leaf, negative photostat.
- Census, November 1775, of a district in Dunmore County made by John Denton., 1 leaf.
- Census, 1775, of a district in Dunmore County made by Thomas Allen., 1 leaf, negative photostat.
- Census, [1775], of a district in Dunmore County made by Henry Nelson., 1 leaf.
- Census, 1775, of a district in Dunmore County made by John Netherton., 2 leaves, negative photostats.
- Commission, 9 January 1776, appointing Alexander Mackir [Machir] a captain in the Dunmore County militia., 1 leaf, positive photostat.
- Letter, 23 January 1776, from Benjamin Wilson, Dunmore County, to Colonel Peter Muhlenberg requesting that he not be commissioned lieutenant in a company of regulars raised in Dunmore County., 2 leaves, negative photostats.
- Letter, 9 February 1776, from Edmund Pendleton, Williamsburg, Virginia, to [Committee of Safety], Dunmore County, informing them that the company of regulars raised there are to be part of the 8th Regiment stationed at Suffolk, Virginia., .
- Letter, 2 April 1776, from Fielding Lewis to [Committee of Safety?], Dunmore County, concerning 174 bushels of salt for Dunmore County., 1 leaf, negative photostat.
- List, 1776, of persons who purchased salt from Abraham Bordt., 3 leaves, negative and positive photostats.
- List, 1776, of persons who purchased salt from Georg Hodell., 4 leaves, 2 copies, negative and positive photostats.
- Letter, n.d., from Jonathan Clark, Dunmore County, to [Committee of Safety?] offering himself as a candidate for the captaincy of the German company being raised., 1 leaf, negative photostat.
- Account, n.d., of the regular officers of Dunmore County., 1 leaf, negative photostat.
- List, n.d., of subscribers for the first independent company of Dunmore County militia., 1 leaf, negative photostat.
- Roster, n.d., of Captain Joseph Bowman's company of militia in the lower district of Dunmore County., 2 leaves, negative photostat.
- Roster, n.d., of Captain Alexander Machir's company of militia in the Strasburg district of Dunmore County., 2 leaves, negative photostats.
- Roster, n.d., of Captain Michael Reader's company of militia, Dunmore County., 2 leaves, negative photostats.
- note, n.d., weight of silver in the hands of Mr. Jon. Clarke., 1 leaf, negative photostat.
- Letter, n.d., from [William Clarke?] of Dunmore County to [the Committee of Safety?] attesting to the writer's loyalty to King George III and deploring the actions of the colonies. Reverse contains notation Proceedings agst. Clarke., 2 leaves, negative photostats.
- Commission, 24 August 1812, for Jacob Savage as lieutenant in 13th Regiment, 7th Brigade, 3rd Division, Shenandoah County, Virginia. Includes note that Savage has taken the oath for his commission., 2 leaves, negative photostats.
- Commission, 25 June 1814, for George Ruddell as captain of the 13th Regiment, 7th Brigade, 3rd Division, Shenandoah County. Includes note that Ruddell has taken the oath for his commission., 2 leaves, negative photostats.